export const ECONOMICSA2017 = [

{
id: "question1",
question:  "1. Now answer the following questions. Economics is regarded as a science because",
A: "its issues can be easily verified by reference to facts.",
B: "it adopts scientific; method in making its analysis.",
C: "its issues are relevant for national development.",
D: "its subject matter studies human behaviour.",
answer: "B. it adopts scientific; method in making its analysis.",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question2",
question:  "2. The opportunity cost of a worker going to the university is",
A: "tuition, fees and books.",
B: "boarding and lodging.",
C: "the wages given up to attend university.",
D: "transportation and entertainment.",
answer: "C. the wages given up to attend university.",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question3",
question:  "3. Which of the following items is not an example of circulating capital?",
A: "Raw material",
B: "Money",
C: "Fuel",
D: "Machinery",
answer: "D. Machinery",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question4",
question:  "4. In a market economy, the problem of what goods to produce is solved primarily by",
A: "directives of the government.",
B: "the pattern of consumers’ spending.",
C: "producers of consumer goods.",
D: "people producing what they want.",
answer: "C. producers of consumer goods.",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question5",
question:  "5. If the weights of five puppies in kilograms are 3.5, 3.0, 4.2, 5.0 and 4.3, then the mean weight of the puppies is",
A: "3.5kg.",
B: "4.0 kg.",
C: "4.2 kg.",
D: "5.0 kg.",
answer: "B. 4.0 kg.",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question6",
question:  "6. If the coefficient of cross elasticity of demand for goods Y and Z is positive, the two goods are",
A: "complements.",
B: "substitutes.",
C: "luxuries.",
D: "inferior.",
answer: "B. substitutes.",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question7",
question:  "7. The difference between demand and wants is in the",
A: "desire for the commodity.",
B: "significance of the commodity.",
C: "ability to pay for the commodity.",
D: "economic value of the commodity.",
answer: "C. ability to pay for the commodity.",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question8",
question:  "8. A demand curve parallel to the Y-axis indicates",
A: "fairly elastic demand.",
B: "perfectly elastic demand.",
C: "perfectly inelastic demand.",
D: "fairly inelastic demand.",
answer: "C. perfectly inelastic demand.",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question9",
question:  "9. Which of the following is an example of derived demand?",
A: "Textbook",
B: "Labour",
C: "Staple food",
D: "Mobile phone",
answer: "B. Labour",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question10",
question:  "10. A rightward shift in the supply curve of a commodity is brought about by an increase in",
A: "the level of technology.",
B: "the price of the commodity.",
C: "Cost of production.",
D: "taxation.",
answer: "B. the price of the commodity.",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question11",
question:  "11. Effective supply is the total amount of a commodity",
A: "from a single producer.",
B: "in the warehouses of producers.",
C: "offered for sale at a market price.",
D: "produced for the market.",
answer: "C. offered for sale at a market price.",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question12",
question:  "12. Price elasticity of supply can be influenced by the following factors except",
A: "time period.",
B: "cost of production.",
C: "size of consumers’ income.",
D: "nature of the product.",
answer: "C. size of consumers’ income.",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question13",
question:  "13. Increase in the supply of a product can be caused by",
A: "change in tastes and fashion of consumers.",
B: "increase in the incomes of consumers.",
C: "a fall in the cost of production.",
D: "increase in the price of a product.",
answer: "D. increase in the price of a product.",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question14",
question:  "14. A rational consumer will purchase a commodity whose price is",
A: "greater than his marginal utility.",
B: "less than his marginal utility.",
C: "equal to his marginal utility.",
D: "equal to his total utility.",
answer: "C. equal to his marginal utility.",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question15",
question:  "15. Parallel markets are usually the result of",
A: "excess supply.",
B: "the activities of rich individuals.",
C: "price legislation.",
D: "inadequate information.",
answer: "C. price legislation.",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question16",
question:  "16. Another term for equilibrium price is",
A: "price floor.",
B: "demand price.",
C: "market clearing price.",
D: "satisfactory price.",
answer: "C. market clearing price.",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question17",
question:  "17. When a firm is enjoying internal economies of scale, its",
A: "total cost of production is increasing as output increases.",
B: "average fixed cost is rising continuously.",
C: "average cost of production decreases as output increases.",
D: "average revenue and marginal revenue arc decreasing.",
answer: "C. average cost of production decreases as output increases.",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question18",
question:  "18. The specialisation of labour enhances production because people",
A: "can concentrate on all goods they can produce belter.",
B: "can efficiently produce their own needs,",
C: "can save time and produce more.",
D: "become experts in all areas of production.",
answer: "C. can save time and produce more.",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question19",
question:  "19. Which of the following can be added to a firm’s profit to obtain total revenue?",
A: "Total variable cost",
B: "Total fixed cost",
C: "Marginal cost",
D: "Total cost",
answer: "D. Total cost",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question20",
question:  "20. The amount of money that a firm receives from the sale of its output is called",
A: "total profit.",
B: "total revenue.",
C: "total cost.",
D: "average revenue.",
answer: "B. total revenue.",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question21",
question:  "21. Which of the following is true of the monopolist?",
A: "His average revenue curve is horizontal",
B: "He determines both price and output",
C: "His demand and marginal revenue curves arc the same",
D: "He determines cither price or output",
answer: "D. He determines cither price or output",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question22",
question:  "22. Equity shares form the bulk of the capital of a",
A: "private company.",
B: "public company.",
C: "statutory company.",
D: "limited partnership.",
answer: "B. public company.",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question23",
question:  "23. If a state-owned firm is sold through the stock market, the organisation becomes a",
A: "partnership.",
B: "private company.",
C: "public limited company.",
D: "public corporation.",
answer: "C. public limited company.",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question24",
question:  "24. The total number of people of working age who are willing and prepared to work at a given wage rale is the",
A: "labour force.",
B: "supply of labour.",
C: "demand for labour.",
D: "occupational demand for labour.",
answer: "A. labour force.",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question25",
question:  "25. A civil engineer who accepts to leach elementary science in a primary school because he cannot get a paid engineering job is an example of",
A: "structural unemployment.",
B: "disguised unemployment.",
C: "residual unemployment.",
D: "frictional unemployment.",
answer: "A. structural unemployment.",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question26",
question:  "26. Which of the following is an implication of a large population?",
A: "Decrease in crime rate",
B: "Increase in food supply",
C: "Decrease in standard of living",
D: "Decrease in cost of living",
answer: "C. Decrease in standard of living",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question27",
question:  "27. Hit system of agriculture which involves the cultivation of crops and rearing or animals for family consumption only is termed",
A: "peasant farming.",
B: "plantation agriculture.",
C: "commercial farming.",
D: "subsistence farming.",
answer: "D. subsistence farming.",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question28",
question:  "28. An industry whose product loses considerable weight after processing must be sited close to",
A: "the source of finance.",
B: "a ready market.",
C: "a power station.",
D: "the source of raw material.",
answer: "B. a ready market.",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question29",
question:  "29. Which of the following is a threat to the existence of middlemen?",
A: "Consumers’ cooperative societies",
B: "Producers’ cooperative societies",
C: "Sales agents",
D: "Large scale producers",
answer: "A. Consumers’ cooperative societies",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question30",
question:  "30. In an industrial area, the location of industries is particularly influenced by",
A: "extent of the division of labour.",
B: "external economies.",
C: "internal economies.",
D: "nearness to financial institution.",
answer: "B. external economies.",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question31",
question:  "31. Which of the following is a transfer income?",
A: "Dividends",
B: "Rent",
C: "Pensions",
D: "Interest",
answer: "C. Pensions",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question32",
question:  "32. The value-added method used in measuring national income is to",
A: "measure output at factor cost.",
B: "avoid multiple counting of output.",
C: "deduct depreciation of capital assets.",
D: "add net factor income from abroad.",
answer: "D. avoid multiple counting of output.",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question33",
question:  "33. Which of the following is most likely to be of benefit to a debtor?",
A: "Inflation",
B: "Deflation",
C: "Revaluation",
D: "Monetization",
answer: "A. Inflation",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question34",
question:  "34. The formula Y = C + I + G + (X-M) will be appropriate for measuring national income using the",
A: "Income approach.",
B: "expenditure approach.",
C: "output approach.",
D: "factor approach.",
answer: "B. expenditure approach.",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question35",
question:  "35. A measure of the value of money in an economy is the",
A: "size of workers’ income.",
B: "general price level.",
C: "total level of savings.",
D: "total amount of loans granted by the banks.",
answer: "B. general price level.",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question36",
question:  "36. One characteristic of money is that it should be",
A: "a standard for deferred payment.",
B: "stable in value.",
C: "a store of value.",
D: "acceptable by the central bank.",
answer: "D. acceptable by the central bank.",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question37",
question:  "37. A financial institution that specializes in giving loans using real assets as collateral security is a",
A: "development bank.",
B: "insurance company.",
C: "central bank.",
D: "mortgage bank.",
answer: "D. mortgage bank.",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question38",
question:  "38. The function that distinguishes commercial banks from the central bank is that the former",
A: "is a lender of last resort.",
B: "accepts deposits from the public.",
C: "services the public debt.",
D: "regulates foreign exchange.",
answer: "B. accepts deposits from the public.",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question39",
question:  "39. Direct taxes include",
A: "excise duty.",
B: "ad valorem tax.",
C: "specific tax.",
D: "capital gains tax.",
answer: "D. capital gains tax.",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question40",
question:  "40. The control of aggregate demand through changes in government spending and tax rates is referred to as",
A: "monetary policy.",
B: "government policy.",
C: "income policy,",
D: "fiscal policy.",
answer: "D. fiscal policy.",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question41",
question:  "41. Which of the following is not a feature of economic underdevelopment?",
A: "Monocultural economy",
B: "High productivity",
C: "Low life expectancy",
D: "Income inequality",
answer: "B. High productivity",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question42",
question:  "42. One way of speeding up the economic development of a country is by encouraging",
A: "the consumption of consumer goods.",
B: "early marriages.",
C: "the importation of more consumer goods.",
D: "savings and investment.",
answer: "D. savings and investment.",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question43",
question:  "43. Dumping in international trade occurs when a foreign firm sells",
A: "above its cost of production at home and abroad.",
B: "below its cost of production at home and abroad.",
C: "more goods to a country than the country has need of.",
D: "below its cost of production in a foreign market.",
answer: "D. below its cost of production in a foreign market.",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question44",
question:  "44. Infant industries can be described as",
A: "newly established industries.",
B: "industries enjoying tax holidays.",
C: "industries producing baby products.",
D: "newly commercialised industries.",
answer: "A. newly established industries.",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question45",
question:  "45. Modern international trade is based on the principle of",
A: "absolute cost advantage.",
B: "comparative cost advantage.",
C: "terms of trade.",
D: "balance of trade.",
answer: "B. comparative cost advantage.",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question46",
question:  "46. Which of the following items is recorded in a country’s current account section of the balance of payments?",
A: "Investment income",
B: "Foreign direct investment",
C: "Long-term capital flows",
D: "Long-term loans",
answer: "A. Investment income",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question47",
question:  "47. One problem facing the economic integration of countries in West Africa is the",
A: "presence of large and developed markets.",
B: "uneven development among West African countries.",
C: "existence of different central banks in the countries.",
D: "failure of labour to move freely in the region.",
answer: "B. uneven development among West African countries.",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question48",
question:  "48. One objective of the Organisation of Petroleum Exporting Countries (OPEC) is to",
A: "harmonise and stabilize oil prices.",
B: "ensure excess supply of oil to consuming countries.",
C: "subsidise oil prices in member countries.",
D: "assist member countries to exploit oil",
answer: "A. harmonise and stabilize oil prices.",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question49",
question:  "49. Which of the following resources is renewable?",
A: "Coal",
B: "Iron ore",
C: "Rice",
D: "Limestone",
answer: "C. Rice",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question50",
question:  "50. The negative effects of mining in West Africa does not include",
A: "reafforestation in rural communities.",
B: "land degradation.",
C: "destruction of farmlands.",
D: "pollution of water bodies",
answer: "A. reafforestation in rural communities.",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},


]